舰长  远程传感器有反应
Captain, new contact on long-range sensors.
克里弗星战舰快速靠近
Creaver battleship closing fast.
缩小
Demagnify.
先知
Oracle...
如果开战的话船员生存几率有多大
Chances for crew survival if we engage?
我们的武器系统已经报废了
Our weapons systems are disabled.
外星舰队有更先进的武器
The alien vessel has superior firepower.
存活几率1%
Chances of survival... .1%.
这预期值还真乐观
That's a rosy prediction.
生存要紧  择日再战
We will live to fight another day.
准备曲速撤退
Prepare for flash warp.
麦克斯舰长  克洛伊上尉
Captain Max, lieutenant Chloe
还没有从月球瞬移回来
hasn't teleported back from ariel's moon.
暂停曲速撤退
Hold flash warp.
我们不能丢下她
We're not leaving without her.
但是长官  如果撤退不及时
But, sir, if we don't warp in time,
人类就会灭亡
all of humanity will be lost.
如果我们不等克洛伊上尉
And if we don't wait for lieutenant Chloe,
我们的人性就会灭亡
our humanity will be lost.
舰长  克里弗星战舰发射了离子鱼雷
Captain, the creavers have fired ion torpedoes.
启动保护盾  准备战斗
Shields up. Man battle stations.
九秒后击中
Impact in nine seconds.
克洛伊上尉情况如何
Status on lieutenant Chloe.
她瞬移了  长官  回到了战舰上
She teleported, sir. She's back on our ship.
启动曲速光
Initiate flash warp.
启动三  二  一
Warping in three, two... One.
成功撤退
Warp successful.
克洛伊上尉  你回来了
Lieutenant Chloe, you're back.
我的冲击波枪也回来了
And so is my thorian blaster.
为什么
Why?
我已经是克里弗星的一员了
I'm with the creavers now.
这艘战舰
And this ship...
现在由我指挥
Is under my command.
真是太酷了
That was so freakin' cool.
感谢各位今天做我的下属
Thank you for serving under me today
参加"星云九号"粉丝体验
on the "Nebula-9" fan experience.
请回到化妆间
Please return to the dressing rooms
将制服交给服务员
and leave your uniforms with the attendant.
愿幸运
And may fortune...
指引你们的航程
guide your journey.
瞧这个先知舱
Check out the oracle pod.
老天  这个先知看起来跟真人一样
Man, the oracle looks so real.
我觉得这就是真人
I think she is real.
我觉得她死了
And I think she's dead.
给你
And here you go.
多谢  我是你的头号粉丝
Thanks. I'm your number-one fan.
多谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
粉到什么地步了
How far they fall.
好了  想签在哪里
All right. Where do you want it?
可以签在我的胸口上吗
Could you sign my chest?
哇  居然真的吸引了你的注意
Wow. That actually got your attention.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
如果你接了电话  你就会知道了
You'd know if you'd answer your phone.
如果你想要你专属的《斯道姆季节》签名版
Listen, if you want your very own signed copy of "Storm Season,"
我很乐意安排一个私下签售会
I'd be happy to arrange a private signing.
套上笔帽  卡塞尔  这里有谋杀案
Cap your pen, Castle. There's been a murder here.
新星科幻大会吗
Here at supernovacon?
够劲
Shiny.
你得承认
You gotta admit,
这里简直是搞谋杀的绝佳场所啊
this is a genius place to commit a murder.
穿上戏服
I mean, you don a costume,
干掉目标
strike down your intended target,
立刻便能融入人群消失
and then melt into the crowd unseen.
听起来你好像真想过这事啊  卡塞尔
You sound like you've actually thought about this, Castle.
我以前经常来这里
I used to come here a lot.
阿丽克西斯和我每年都会盛装前来
Alexis and I would come here every year and dress up.
你应该瞧她的可爱样子
You should've seen her,
就像个小号的莉亚公主
like a little pint-sized princess Leia.
你扮什么
And you were?
当然是黑武士了
Oh, Darth Vader, of course.
被害人是谁
So who is our victim?
章鱼博士终于抓住了蜘蛛侠吗
Did Doc Ock finally catch up with Spider-Man?
想想电视上的飞船
Think more tv starship.
博格人的攻击
Oh! Um, Borg Attack.
赛昂人  拜托说是六号复制人
Cylon skinjob? Please say number six.
不是  是星云九号
Nope. "Nebula-9."
真的假的
Really?
不好意思  "星云九号"值得这么折腾吗
I'm sorry. How is "Nebula-9" worthy of all this?
十几年前这剧就被砍了
I mean, they were canceled over a decade ago
才播了12集  12集都太多了
after 12 episodes, which was 12 episodes too many.
我以为你会是粉丝
I thought you would be a fan.
我是优秀科幻的粉丝
I'm a fan of good sci-fi--
《星际迷航》《银河战星》
"Star trek," "Battlestar,"
乔斯·韦登的剧[指代《萤火虫》  大叔主演的]
That Joss Whedon show.
但是《星云九号》  不行
But "Nebula-9"? No, no.
全是虚假情节加上生硬的演技
It's all phony melodrama and lifeless acting.
好吧  这艘战舰挺酷的
Okay, this is a cool ship.
剧很差劲  但是战舰够酷
The show is still lame, but this is a cool ship.
-来啦  -嘿
- Yo. - Hey.
被害人是谁
So who's our vic?
安娜贝尔·柯林斯  28岁
Anabelle Collins. She's, uh, 28.
看起来是先被杀害  然后被放置在舱里
Looks like she was killed and then stashed in that pod.
她是这次"星云九号"
She's the one who put together this whole "Nebula-9"
粉丝体验活动的发起人
fan experience re-enactment thing.
道具场景都挺好  可惜主题定错了
An impressive if misguided effort.
同意  哥们
With you, bro.
来个《银翼杀手》体验嘛
Give me "Blade Runner"--
一个拥有性感复制人  昏暗反乌托邦式的未来
A bleak, dystopian future with sexy replicants.
对吧  你呢  贝克特
Right? How about you, Beckett?
你觉得...
What do you...
有找到家属吗
Have you found next of kin?
正打算去
Actually on my way to do that.
帕穆特  很高兴见到你
Perlmutter, good to see you.
我可不太高兴见到你
Ah, if only the feeling were mutual.
知道死亡时间吗
So when was she killed?
鉴于肝脏的温度
Well, based on liver temp,
介于昨晚10点到11点
last night between 10:00 and 11:00 p.M.
更大的问题是  她是如何被杀的
The bigger issue is how she was killed.
我相信死因是
Now I believe death came by way
心脏处这个
of this rather fascinating
小直径的有趣伤口
small-diameter puncture to her heart.
刺伤
Stab wound.
卡塞尔  动动脑筋  这如何解释
Oh, Castle, think. How would that explain
伤口周围的一级烧伤
the first-degree burns on the skin around the wound?
这可能是近距离枪击造成的烧伤
That could be powder burns from a close-range gunshot.
但烧伤应该有火药的痕迹
Yeah, but the burns should have gunpowder stippling,
颗粒会被烙进肉里
particulates seared into the flesh.
而且还应该会有溅出的血迹
Not only that, there would be blood spatter.
那到底是什么致伤的呢
So what caused the wound?
全无头绪
No clue.
从没见过这样的伤痕
Never seen anything quite like it.
回去验尸之后应该能有些结果
I should know more once I get her on the slab.
我刚给目击证人录完口供
So I just finished taking witnesses' statements.
他们之中没人认识死者
Uh, none of these folks knew the victim
也没人在死亡时间段出现在这里过
or were here during the time of death.
我们必须找到符合这两项要求的人
Yeah, we're gonna have to find witnesses that were.
一定有人见过凶手
Someone must have seen the killer
昨晚进入或离开这里
entering or leaving the ship last night.
但我们该怎么找这些人呢
Yeah, but how would we locate them?
这里有几千号人在现场
There's thousands of people here.
我们可以在"星云9号"的
You know what? You could leave a message
影友网站发个帖
on the "Nebula-9" fan site
问问昨晚十点到十一点
asking for anyone that was here
有谁来过这里
between 10:00 and 11:00 last night.
告诉他们  我们将在飞船前
And just let them know that you're gonna meet them
跟他们见个面
at the front of the ship.
"星云9号"影友站
"Nebula-9" fan site?
对呀
Yeah.
我恰巧知道他们有个非常忠实的粉丝...
I understand that they have a very loyal fan...
粉丝团
Fan base.
那是...
Is that...
加布里埃尔·沃特斯  即麦克斯舰长的扮演者
Gabriel Winters, A.K.A. the real Captain Max Rennard.
他认识死者
He knew the victim.
还有呢
And?
我本想找他问话
Oh, I tried to talk to him,
但他说他需要几分钟来
but he said he needed a minute
"思索人类生命的脆弱性"
to "muse upon the fragile nature of human life."
现在已经过去好几分钟了
Well, his minute is up.
你好
Hi. Um...
沃特斯先生  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Mr. Winters, I'm Detective Kate Beckett and--
我伤心极了
I'm devastated,
被痛苦吞噬
ravaged by sorrow.
这让我想起第六集里
I'm reminded of the moment when First Officer Tate
塔特大副被吸入虫洞的时刻
was sucked into that wormhole in episode 6.
只是这次是真的有人死了
Except in this case, someone actually died.
是的
Yeah.
我们知道你认识安娜贝尔
Now I understand that you knew Anabelle.
知道有谁有杀害她动机的吗
Do you have any idea who could've done this to her?
不知道
No idea.
安娜贝尔是个非常棒的人
Anabelle was spectacular in every way.
当"星云9号"被砍的时候
When "Nebula-9" was canceled--
不公正地被砍  我必须说
unjustly, I might add--
她曾试图挽回
she kept interest in the show alive.
没有她我该怎么办呀
How will I go on without her?
怎么继续活下去吗
Go on living?
怎么继续开展粉丝体验会
Go on doing the fan experience.
几个月前  她跟我取得联系
She contacted me a few months ago,
邀请我参加剧迷体验会
asked me to be a part of this.
我对能回到"星云9号"的世界感到非常兴奋
I was thrilled to give back to the "Nebula-9" community.
你上一次见到她是什么时候
When was the last time you saw her?
昨晚九点左右
About 9:00 last night,
体验会结束的时候
after the fan experience ended.
之后我就回酒店了  整晚都没再出门
Then I went back to my hotel, stayed in for the night.
我上一次见到安娜贝尔的时候
Last time I saw Anabelle,
她独自站在桥上
she was alone on the bridge.
愿幸运...  指引她的航程
And may fortune... guide her journey.
但体验会必须继续
But the show must go on.
什么时候我们才能恢复正常运作呢
When do you think we can get this back up and running?
很快
Soon?
对吗
Ish?
到时我们会通知你
We'll let you know.
在此期间  我想问问
In the meantime,
你认识安娜贝尔的任何家庭成员吗
did you know any of Anabelle's family members?
不认识
Nah.
但她的朋友奥德丽和戴维斯
But her friends Audrey and Davis
在大厅运营"星云9号"的展位
run the "Nebula-9" Booth down on the floor.
解散
Dismissed.
这真是太不幸了
It's just so awful.
从高中开始她就是我的挚友
She's been my best friend since high school.
是她把我介绍给戴维斯的
She introduced me to Davis.
她是我俩的红娘
She's the reason we're together.
是的  我们因为"星云9号"成为好友
Yeah, we bonded over "Nebula-9."
我们都非常喜欢这部剧
We all loved the show.
所以  当安娜贝尔开办粉丝俱乐部时
So... When Anabelle started the fan club,
我俩都去帮忙了
we helped out.
就是那时  我俩开始恋爱的
And it just kind of took off from there.
最近她有什么奇怪的举止吗
Did you notice any unusual behavior lately?
昨天早上见到她的时候  她看起来很沮丧
I saw her yesterday morning, and she seemed really upset.
-为什么事  -我也不知道
- About what? - I don't know.
她只说有一个她信任的人背叛了她
All she said was that someone she had trusted had betrayed her.
知道是谁吗  她跟谁有纠葛吗
Any idea who? Was she involved with anyone?
我不知道
Not that I know of.
安娜贝尔有仇家吗
Did Anabelle have any enemies?
有一些剧迷  曾经给她发出过威胁信
There were those fans, the ones that sent all the threats.
什么威胁信
What threats?
在安娜贝尔开办粉丝俱乐部之后
After the fan club took off, Anabelle bought
她以很低的价格把剧集的版权买下了
the rights to the show for practically nothing
并开始拍摄新的"星云9号"网络版
and started making new "Nebula-9" Webisodes
演员就是她和我俩三个人
Starring the three of us.
就是从剧集被砍的剧情继续往下拍
You know, picking up where the show left off,
像是对原作的一种致敬
like as a tribute.
但并不是所有人都这么看待网络版
Not everyone saw it that way.
安娜贝尔收过一些非常糟糕的电邮
Anabelle got some pretty ugly e-mails.
有多糟
How ugly?
有一些甚至威胁要杀了她
Some were death threats.
戴维斯可真不是开玩笑的
Davis wasn't kidding about these e-mails.
你听这个
Listen to this.
"你们的网络版真是
"Your so-called webisodes
对原作记忆的亵渎
desecrate the memory of 'Nebula-9'
为此  你们会付出沉重代价"
and you should pay the ultimate price."
我不确定  卡塞尔
I don't know, Castle.
你真的认为安娜贝尔会是
Do you honestly believe that Anabelle was killed
被愤怒的剧迷杀死的吗
by an angry "Nebula-9" Fan?
我认为  如果一个人会迷"星云9号"
I think if you like "Nebula-9,"
那么他就足够疯狂去杀人
You're crazy enough to kill, yeah.
你为什么对这部剧评价如此之低
Why are you so down on the show?
好吧  我来跟你解释一下
Uh, okay, well, let's see,
因为它剧情俗套
Because it's cheesy,
无视物理法则
It ignores the laws of physics...
也没有好的故事叙述
and good storytelling,
更不用说...
not to mention--
好了  我知道了
Okay, I got it.
帕穆特的来电  说有消息给我们
It's Perlmutter. He's got something for us.
凯特·贝克特
Kate Beckett?!
凯贝克
K-bex!
我就知道是你
I knew it was you.
亨利·巴内特  哇
oh, Henry Barnett. Wow.
真是多年未见啊
It's been... years.
自从我们在斯坦福大学的第一个学期后就没见过
Since our first semester at Stanford.
凯贝克
K-bex?
我  我...
I, uh, I--
我们晚点再叙旧行吗
Do you think we could catch up later?
我其实是为公事来的
I'm actually here for work.
原来如此
Oh, well, that explains
难怪你没穿"星云9号"的制服
why you aren't wearing your "Nebula-9" outfit.
你...
You, uh...
你有套"星云9号"制服
You have a "Nebula-9" Outfit?
她有好多套呢
Oh, she had a few.
她是个超级粉丝
She was a mega fan.
你真该看看她扮克洛伊上尉的样子
You should've seen her as lieutenant Chloe.
等等  真有看的
Oh, wait. You can.
记得我们拍的那张合照吗
Remember that photo we all took?
我特意带过来求签名的
I brought it to get it signed.
拍的是当年的我们
It's us from back in the day.
是不是超级无敌棒
Isn't it frakin' awesome?
是超级无敌傻吧
It's frakin' something.
亨利  把那张照片给我
Henry, I need that photo.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
就当是纽约警局的官方要求
It's official NYPD business.
别让我再说一遍
Don't make me ask again.
谢谢
Thank you.
我曾是"星云9号"粉丝  有什么大不了的
So I was "Nebula-9" fan. Big deal.
你可不仅是个粉丝
Oh, you were beyond a fan.
你穿上了他们的戏服  你
You dressed up in costume. You.
好吧  是的
Okay, yes,
我曾是个热爱科幻  喜穿戏服的呆粉
I was a sci-fi loving, costume-wearing geek,
而且你知道吗
And you know what?
我并不以此或是"星云9号"为耻
Not ashamed of it or of "Nebula-9."
不管你怎么想  那可真是部神剧
Despite what you think, it was an awesome show.
我告诉你吧
I'll tell you what,
我可以原谅你糟糕的品位
I'll forgive you your terrible taste
只要你...
If you...
再为我穿一次"星云9号"的戏服
try on that "Nebula-9" Costume for me.
做梦去吧你
In your dreams.
你瞧瞧我的生活
Look at my life.
美梦都成真了
my dreams come true.
帕穆特
Perlmutter.
贝克特警探
Detective Beckett.
帕穆特
Perlmutter.
非警探  卡塞尔
And non-detective castle.
你查明死因了吗
So do you have a cause of death?
是死于灼伤
It was a burn,
直接灼损了皮肤组织  肌肉和骨头
a burn that penetrated tissue, muscle, and bone,
留下这样一个圆柱形的完美伤口
leaving this perfectly cylindrical hole.
什么东西会造成那样的灼伤呢
Well, what kind of burn does that?
是高度红外线辐射造成的
Well, one created by high levels of infrared radiation.
高度的热量把血管都灼烧损坏了
The--the blood vessels were cauterized from the intense heat.
你是说...
Are you saying--
她是被光炮杀死的吗
She was killed by a phaser?
虽然我很不愿意承认
Well, as much as it pains me,
但卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle is...
说得有点道理
marginally correct.
她是被高强度激光束杀死的
She was killed by a high-intensity laser beam.
发生在科幻大会上的科幻式真谋杀
A real sci-fi murder... at a sci-fi convention.
真是越来越精彩了
Just keeps getting better.
她怎么可能是被激光杀死的呢
How is it possible that she's killed by a laser?
很简单  有人用激光枪朝她开了一枪
Easy. Someone shot her with a laser gun.
那在现实中是不存在的  卡塞尔
Real ones don't exist, Castle.
实际上  是存在的
Actually, they do.
有一种高级的激光炮
There is an advanced tetical laser
可以从5英里外在墙上射出一个洞
that could melt a hole in a tank from 5 miles away.
我在报上读到过  那东西像卡车那么大
Read about it. It's as big as a truck.
是的  但显然某人造出了
Yes, well, obviously someone has constructed
一种便携式的小版
a portable, hand-held version.
比如谁呢
Like who?
我们查一下"星云9号"的疯狂粉丝们的来信吧
Let's go back to the e-mails of the crazed "Nebula-9" fans.
我刚说"疯狂粉丝"
And when I say "Crazed fans,"
其实  并不是指你
I'm--I'm not referring to you.
你  只不过是超级粉丝
You... are a mega fan.
你还有脸说我
Nice one coming from the guy
你自己浴室里还藏着一个真人大小的波巴·加特呢
with a life-size boba fett in his bathroom.
反击得有道理  总之
Point taken. Anyway...
或许这些粉丝之一
perhaps one of these fans,
被安娜贝尔制作的毁原作的网络剧激怒
enraged by Anabelle's blasphemous webisodes,
不知怎么弄来个真的激光枪
somehow fashioned a functioning thorian blaster
然后  为了报复
And, in an act of divine retribution,
就用"星云9号"中出现过的武器杀死了安娜贝尔
said killer shot Anabelle with the very weapon featured on "Nebula-9."
编的很有意思
Interesting theory,
但我们已经询问过所有的疯狂粉丝
but we have interviewed all of those crazed fans,
他们都有不在场证明
and they all have alibis.
好吧  那或许不是疯狂粉丝
Okay, well, then maybe it wasn't a crazed fan.
但是
but...
事实就是
the fact is,
有人用激光枪杀死了安娜贝尔
someone did zap Anabelle with some kind of...laser blaster.
我去找烟草火器爆炸物管理局的人
I will talk to A.T.F.
看他们知不知道有人持有...
and see if they've heard of anyone possessing a...
激光枪
Laser blaster.
有效的激光武器
A functional laser weapon.
与此同时  希望莱恩和埃斯波西托
In the mean time, hopefully, Ryan and Esposito
在粉丝聚集地找到了一些目击证人
have found some witnesses by posting on the fan site.
她名叫安娜贝尔·柯林斯
Her name is Anabelle Collins.
你见过她出现在这里吗
Did you see her in this area
时间大约是昨晚10点到11点
between 10:00 and 11:00 P.M. last night?
好吧  我再重复一遍问题
Um... Let me repeat the question.
首先  小姐  我想问你
First of all, ma'am, I must ask you,
你是怎么把那些叶子都粘在身上的
Uh, how are you keeping those leaves on there like that?
你何不扯下一片看看
Why don't you pull on one and find out?
你到底有没有见过她
Did you see her or not?
他只会说马赛托尼亚语[科幻作品中虚构的种族]
He only speaks Mersatonian.
或许你可以给我翻译一下
Maybe you could translate for me.
我掌握得不怎么好
I'm not really that fluent.
下一个
Next.
昨晚10点到11点  你见过她吗
Did you see her here last night between 10:00 and 11:00?
没有
Nope.
但是
But...
如果还有别的需要我"帮忙"
If there's anything else I can do for you...
请收下我的号码
Here's my number.
记得打给我
Call me.
笔还没还我
You took my pen.
首先我想知道你会说英语吗
Let me begin by asking if you speak english or not.
废话
Obvi.
好吧
Okay.
昨晚10点到11点间你见过这个女人吗
Did you see this woman between 10:00 and 11:00 p.m. last night?
-见过  -你见过
- Yeah.  - You did?
是的  我和朋友们都被她惹怒了
Yeah. My friends and I were totes pissed at her
因为她前一秒还说剧迷体验会已经结束了
Because she told us that the fan experience was closed,
下一秒就把别人带进去了
and then two seconds later, she brought someone inside here.
你能描述一下那个人的相貌吗
Could you describe who she was with?
我能告诉你更多
I can do lots better.
我知道她的名字
I can tell you her name.
史黛芬妮·弗赖伊
Stephanie Frye.
就是在"星云9号"中扮演你的偶像
The actress who played your personal hero
克洛伊上尉的
Lieutenant Chloe
那个女演员
in the original "Nebula-9" Series?
一个目击者看见安娜贝尔和史黛芬妮在
A witness saw Anabelle and Stephanie
大约9:45走进了飞船
walk on to the spaceship set around 9:45.
之后那个目击者还见过她们两个吗
Well, did she see either one of them after that?
没有
No.
史黛芬妮现在是个大明星了
Stephanie's a big movie star now.
她也不再出演"星云9号"了
She's not even involved with "Nebula-9."
她还可能有什么动机呢
What possible motive could she have?
我知道的是  她是最后几个见过
All I know is that she was one of the last people
安娜贝尔的人之一
to see Anabelle alive,
所以我得找她谈谈
So I have to talk to her.
安娜贝尔遇害我也很难过
I'm sad to hear about Anabelle.
我跟她在这种聚会中见过几次
I've met her a few times at conventions like this.
她很可爱
She seemed lovely.
有个目击者说在安娜贝尔遇害之前
We have witness that saw you and Anabelle
你和她一起进了飞船
go into the ship just before she died.
你不会是以为
You don't think--
我们只是想弄清楚当时发生了什么
We're just trying to figure out what happened.
什么也没发生
Nothing happened.
我们只是谈了一会儿  时间很短
We talked. It was a quick conversation.
因为我10点要去走红毯
I had to be on the red carpet 10:00.
你们谈了些什么
What did you talk about?
她问我能不能
She asked if I'd be part
参加这周末的"星云9号"剧迷体验会
of this weekend's "Nebula-9" fan experience.
可你早就跟剧集划清界限了
Yeah, but you'd distanced yourself from the show.
不是吗  我是听说的
Didn't you? I... heard that you did.
别误解我
Well, don't get me wrong,
扮演克洛伊上尉对我的确是个突破
Playing Lieutenant Chloe was my big break,
但是
but...
"星云9号"
"Nebula-9"?
是不会让我成名的
not exactly a career launcher.
我懂的
I know.
现在我终于
Now that I'm finally
逐渐成为了受人重视的女演员
being taken seriously as an actress,
我自然不会回去
I couldn't go back.
这会有损我的形象
It would harm my image.
所以我拒绝了安娜贝尔  她也理解
So I told Anabelle no. She understood.
但我不太理解
Well, I'm not sure I do.
既然她知道你很可能拒绝
Why would she even ask
她为什么还要开口呢
if she knew you'd refuse?
她那是走投无路
She was desperate.
她说如果请不来一个
She said she'd have to shut it down
原班阵容中的演员她就得把这活动停掉了
if she didn't have an original cast member.
不是有麦克斯舰长吗
Yeah, but what about Captain Max?
加布里埃尔·沃特斯  他不是参加了吗
Gabriel, uh, Winters-- she had him, didn't she?
加布里埃尔是个有点麻烦的人
Gabriel is a complicated guy.
她虽然没细说
I mean, she didn't go into detail,
但是他们俩之间有矛盾
but she was having problems with him.
他们俩一直有矛盾
She was having problems with him all right.
据说加布里埃尔去粉丝体验会的时候
Word is that Gabriel was showing up late
不仅迟到了
to the fan experience,
而且还喝醉了
and drunk.
麦克斯舰长竟然喝醉了
Captain Max was drunk?
何止是喝醉
Among other transgressions.
他昨天本来都没去"星云9号"
He was actually a no-show to the "Nebula-9" yesterday,
是安娜贝尔去酒店把他叫醒的
and Anabelle had to rouse him from his hotel room,
他当时正和两个克洛伊上尉一丝不挂地睡着呢
where he was passed out naked with two Lieutenant Chloes.
看来幸运真在指引着这家伙的航程啊
I think fortune was definitely guiding his journey.
不能因为他有些不好的行为
Just because he exhibited some bad behavior
就认为他有杀人的动机
doesn't mean that that was motive for murder.
不过我刚跟加布里埃尔的经纪人谈过
Well, except that I just spoke to Gabriel's agent.
安娜贝尔昨天给她打了电话  威胁要开了加布
Anabelle called her yesterday, threatening to fire him.
因此他就杀了她
And so he killed her?
情况是这样的
Well, here's the thing,
加布是个过气的演员
the guy is a washed up actor.
自从那部剧被砍后就几乎没工作过
He's barely worked since the show was canceled.
他一天跑20场剧迷体验会
He does, what, 20 fan experiences a day
才挣500块钱
at 500 bucks a shot?
如果安娜贝尔把他开了
If Anabelle took that away from him,
他就什么都没了
he'd have nothing.
好的  伙计们  谢了
Okay, guys. Thanks.
安娜贝尔说她被她信任的人出卖了
Anabelle said she was betrayed by someone she trusted.
或许那个人就是麦克斯舰长
Maybe that was Captain Max.
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
阿丽克西斯
Alexis?
老爸  你在这儿干嘛
Dad? What are you doing here?
你在这儿干嘛  还穿成这样
What are you doing here dressed like that?
我们是havacura  是一群女刺客
We're havacura. It's a tribe of female assassins who--
不穿衣服的女刺客
Don't wear clothes?
你有些小题大作了  而且让我很难堪
You're overreacting. And you're embarrassing me.
我让你难堪  我可是穿着衣服的
Oh, I'm embarrassing you? I'm the one who's dressed.
-老爸  -卡塞尔  我们走吧
- Dad!  - Castle, come on. Let's go.
你没搞错吧  你看见她穿的是什么了吗
Are you kidding me? Do you see what she's wearing?
看见了  也没那么糟
Yeah, it's not that bad.
没那么糟  这画面要我怎么消除啊
Not that bad? How am I gonna unsee that?
如果开战的话船员生存几率有多大
Chances of crew survival if we engage?
我们的武器系统已经报废了
Our weapons systems are disabled.
外星舰队有更先进的武器
The alien vessel has superior firepower.
存活几率  0.1%
Chances of survival-- 0.1%.
这预期值还真乐观
That's a rosy prediction.
生存要紧  择日...
We will live to fight...
我们有访客了
Ah, we have visitors...
他们穿着21世纪的衣服
wearing 21st century garb.
你们是为和平而来
Do you come in peace...
还是有什么高级的阴谋
or is this more creaver trickery?
纽约警察
NYPD.
抱歉了  各位  那么得提前结束了
Sorry, folks, we're gonna have to cut this short.
大家请出去
Everyone out.
这也太离谱了
This is outrageous.
我让你们参加"星云9号"剧迷体验会
I included you in the "Nebula-9" fan experience,
你们却来捣乱
and you ruined it.
沃特斯先生  昨晚10点到11点
Mr. Winters, where were you last night
你在哪里
between 10:00 and 11:00?
别告诉我你在酒店房间里
And don't say your hotel room.
你们不会是在暗示
You can't be insinuating
我跟安娜贝尔的死有关吧
I had something to do with Anabelle's death.
我把知道的都告诉你们了
I told you everything I know.
那你应该不介意交出你的武器
Then you wouldn't mind relinquishing your weapon.
这把钍晶喷气枪是我帮助
This thorian blaster was given to me
解救了女王之后
by the vice chancellor of Loron
欧诺伦国的副总理送给我的
When I helped save the queen..
苍天在上啊
Oh, for the love of pete.
我勒个去
Zap, said the lady.
被抓个正着
You are so busted.
我们的弹道分析师
Hey. So our ballistics guys got together with...
和帕穆特一起测试了那把喷气枪
Perlmutter and tested the blaster.
确定是我们要找的凶器
It's definitely our murder weapon.
我要找到铁证给这家伙定罪
I want to build an iron-clad case against this guy.
叫技术员查一下枪  看看从哪来的
Have tech look at the gun, find out where it came from.
如你所愿
As you wish.
能看出来安娜贝尔为何会觉得受人背叛了
I can see how Anabelle felt betrayed.
某人没有指挥宇宙飞船的资格
Some guys have no business commanding a spaceship.
也说明  有时候人不可貌相
Just goes to show you, sometimes people aren't what they appear to be.
至于阿丽克西斯  关于她的穿着
For Alexis' sake, I hope you're right,
我希望你是对的
given what she was wearing.
卡塞尔  她是个成年女性
Castle, she is a full-grown woman.
我们提到的姑娘
Who, as we speak,
当时周围都是一些汗津津  色迷迷
is being ogled by thousands of sweaty,
乱抛媚眼的男生
lecherous fan boys.
这感觉就是...不对
It's just so... wrong.
我是不是应该指出
Can I just point out the fact
她身上的衣服
that the costume that she was wearing
跟你要求我穿的衣服没什么两样
is not so different from the one that you are asking me to wear?
别这么说嘛
Don't say that!
那...
That...
这两种画面太让人错乱了
It's confusing and disturbing.
听着  我不知道那枪是哪来的
Look, I have no idea where that blaster came from.
真搞笑  东西就别在你腰上
That's funny, since it was on your hip.
我换服装的时候从道具桌上拿的
I grabbed it off the props table when I suited up,
就跟以前一样
Just like I always do.
我又不知道它是真的
I didn't know it was real.
等等
Wait.
你们以为是我杀了她
You guys think I killed her
还把杀人凶器随身带着
and then kept the murder weapon on me?
哪个白痴会这么做
What kind of idiot does that?
那你为什么不告诉我们你和安娜贝尔有矛盾
Why didn't you tell us that you were having problems with Anabelle?
我曾在一部口碑不错的电影里饰演律师
I played a lawyer in a well-regarded film
虽然没能上映
that didn't come out.
总之我了解司法系统
I know about the legal system.
那会让我看起来有罪
That would've just made me look guilty.
那你现在的形象呢
As opposed to how you look now?
我是这样认为的  安娜贝尔受够了
Look, here's what I think-- Anabelle got tired
你的酗酒和寻欢作乐  威胁说要解雇你
of your drunken carousing and threatened to fire you
由于这是你唯一的工作  所以你杀了她
from the only job that you had, so you killed her.
完全错误
None of that is true.
也许寻欢作乐那部分除外
Except maybe the carousing part.
那她没威胁说要解雇你吗
So she didn't threaten to fire you?
当然有  一直嚷嚷着呢
Yes, sure, all the time.
但她从来没兑现过
But she'd never go through with it.
我是"星云9号"的代言人
I'm the face of "Nebula-9."
我是那群疯子在门口能排上
I'm the reason all those lunatics
好几天的唯一理由
line up for days outside of the convention.
对哦  也许他们现在就该去监狱门口排队了
Yes, well, perhaps now they'll line up outside sing sing.
我和安娜贝尔在某些生活方式的
Anabelle and I clashed on certain...
选择上确实有分歧
lifestyle choices.
但我们互相理解
But we had an understanding.
我甚至还帮她和她男朋友
I even got her and her boyfriend
混进了星期三的开幕之夜派对
into the opening night party on Wednesday.
得了吧  她根本没有男朋友
Nice try. She didn't have a boyfriend.
她告诉我她有
She told me she did.
听着  事实是
Look, the fact is,
你有作案工具  动机和机会
you had means, motive, and opportunity.
我们也查了你的旅馆
And we checked with your hotel.
你晚上9点45离开  11点回来
You left at 9:45 p.m. and returned at 11:00.
安娜贝尔就是在这段时间内被害的
That's the exact time window of Anabelle's murder.
我那时是在处理私人问题
I was busy handling a personal issue
而我并不想讨论这事
that I would rather not discuss.
你面临着谋杀的指控
You are facing a murder charge.
好吧  我们已经知道了
Okay, look, we already know about
你和两个克洛伊上尉玩3P的事
the threesome with the Lieutenant Chloe's.
还能糟到什么地步呢
How bad could it be?
这么说吧
Well, let's just say,
我...
My, uh...
对露水情缘的抵抗力
weakness for fleeting romance
在昨晚已经弱到了不得不就医的地步
left me with a burning desire to see my doctor last night.
看来还真能更糟
And it just got worse.
医生确认了他的不在场证明
So the doctor confirms his alibi.
案发当时  医生在给加布里埃尔
He was dosing Gabriel with antibiotics
注射抗生素
during our time-of-death window.
加布里埃尔说安娜贝尔
Gabriel said that Anabelle
和她的男友一起去的派对
went to the party with her boyfriend,
可没有任何迹象表明她正在谈恋爱
but there's no evidence that she was in a relationship.
电邮里没有
There's nothing in her e-mails,
电话  短信都没有
phone calls, or texts.
还有那天她说
And the very next day, she said
有人背叛了她的信任
someone had betrayed her trust.
也许她指的是神秘男友
Maybe she meant the secret boyfriend.
不管他是谁  他都没有主动站出来
Whoever he is, he never came forward,
这就很可疑
and that is suspicious.
我们的技术员有消息了
Our tech guys caught a break.
他们拆了喷气枪
They took apart the gun
在其中的一个零件上
and they traced the serial number
找到了序列号
on one of the components.
生产商把货运去了布朗克斯的一个地址
The manufacturer shipped it to an address in the Bronx.
我和卡塞尔去那里看看
All right, Castle and I will go check this out.
你们俩去大会的吧台
You guys go to the convention center bar
派对就是在那儿开的
where the party was being held
看看有没有人能认出当晚谁和安娜贝尔在一起
and see if you can I.D. who Anabelle was with.
-马上去  -好的
- Right on. - All right.
我告诉你  就是比你好
Better with you, man. I'm telling you.
这里就像地狱的万圣节
This is like the Halloween from hell.
是啊  对你来说似乎是档次低了点
Oh, yeah, this is probably too lowbrow for you, huh?
你可能喜欢去那种
You're probably into that
无聊的知识分子科幻聚会
Boring-ass intellectual kind of sci-fi,
像是"变种异煞"或是"2001"
like "Gattaca" or "2001."
还有"庞然大物"  那是啥玩意
The monolith-- what the hell was that?
别问我
Don't ask me.
不不  宝剑和魔法比较是我的菜
No, no, swords and sorcery, that's more my thing,
就比如"魔戒"
like, uh, "Lord of the Rings."
是啊  我看你就像个小精灵
Yeah, I could probably see you as an elf
或霍比特人
or a Hobbit.
见过  她和她的同伴在包间
Yeah. Served her and her date in a private room.
看起来挺和谐  不过
Looked pretty cozy, but then, uh,
后来她一个人在吧台  眼睛哭肿了
later she was alone at the bar, crying her eyes out.
那个约会对象  你能描述下他的样子吗
This date of hers, can you describe him?
当然了
Sure can.
就像那样
Looked like that.
克里弗吗
A creaver?
什么
A who?
"星云九号"里邪恶的外星种族
The evil alien race from "Nebula-9."
很肮脏的生物
Nasty creatures.
它们会将你生吞活剥
They'll eat you face off while you're still alive
然后把你的器官喂给幼子
And then serve your organs to their young.
谢谢你的解释  还有什么吗
Good to know. Is that all?
她有一张紫色的贵宾卡
Had one of these purple V.I.P. Badges.
很独特
Pretty exclusive.
发行不超过几千张
Can't be more than a few hundred of them.
"危险  请勿进入"
"Danger. Do not enter."
那不正是你想看到的标志嘛
Well, that is just the sort of sign you'd expect to see
挂在制作激光枪的邪恶天才的老巢门口
On the lair of an evil laser-gun-making genius.
里面漆黑一片
It's pitch-black inside,
但门却是半开的
But the door is partially open.
我猜这是在请我们进去  你说呢
I would say that's an invitation. Wouldn't you?
还是以防万一吧
Just in case it isn't.
纽约市警察局  有人在吗
NYPD. Anyone here?
我们应该好好留心那张标牌的
Perhaps we should have heeded that very wise sign.
举起手来
Raise your hands!
准备受死吧
Prepare to die!
纽约警局
NYPD.
放下武器
Put down your weapons.
你们看到没
Did you see that?
这一切都如此完美
It worked perfectly.
这是以星级驱逐舰的瞄准系统
It's modeled on the targeting system
为模型设计的
Of a machbarian star destroyer.
我猜想你的意思是不会杀我们了
So I take it we're not gonna die.
用远程控制的激光棒杀人吗  不会的
From remote-controlled laser pointers? No.
但是它足以吓跑入侵者
But it's perfect to scare away intruders.
国际快递的客服来的时候
You should have seen the U.P.S. Guy.
差点吓尿了
He almost wet himself.
打扰了  先生
Excuse me. Mister...
我叫唐纳利  本杰明·唐纳利
Donnelly. Benjamin Donnelly.
专为有眼光的科幻小说狂热者
Purveyor of sci-fi hardware
提供硬件的承办商
For the discriminating enthusiast.
你们想要什么
So what can I interest you in?
克林贡的刀具
A Klingon Batliff, perhaps?
赛轮牌激光枪
A cylon laser pistol?
还是一把双刃军刀
A double-bladed lightsaber?
你这儿还卖双刃军刀啊
You have a double-bladed lightsaber?
事实上  我们正在寻找钍晶喷气枪
Actually, we're looking for a thorian blaster.
一位很有眼光的女士
The woman has taste.
等离子的信号枪加上三层内核
Plasma pistol with a tri-skellium core--
周身都无比精准
Accurate down to the last detail.
杀人的时候也很精准吗
Including its ability to kill?
你说什么
Excuse me?
我们正在调查一起谋杀案
We're investigating a murder,
我们发现凶器是从你这儿买的
And we traced the weapon back to you.
我制作这些纯粹为了娱乐
I created this for entertainment use only.
从没想过用它伤人
I never intended for it to hurt anybody.
钍晶喷气枪不会杀人  杀人的是使用者
Thorian blasters don't kill. People do.
货物一经卖出  我概不负责
I can't be responsible once they leave my shop.
是啊  那是一把超赞的枪
Yes, well, that is an amazing piece of weaponry...
但我再也不想使用它了
That I never want to fire again.
-等等  你说你用过它了  -是啊
- Wait. You fired it? - Oh, yeah.
你当时带了适当的护具吗
Were you wearing proper protection?
什么护具
What?
没有  为什么要带  什么样的护具
N-no. Why? Wh-what-- what kind of protection?
不碍事的
You'll be fine.
你卖出了多少把
How many of those have you sold?
我只制作了两把可以正常使用的
I only made two that were fully functional.
其中一把在这个箱子里
One in the case here.
另一把  星期三晚上我卖给了一位收藏者
The other, I sold to a collector Wednesday night.
你知道他的名字吗
Do you have a name?
萨姆  赛斯  还是西蒙  像丹麦人的名字
Sam? Seth? Simon? Something Essey.
你能描述下他的样子吗
You think you could describe him?
不能  他当时穿着戏服
No. He was in costume.
我猜猜  他是扮成了克里弗吗
Let me guess. Creaver?
是的
Yeah.
他开着越野车  不知道这有没有用
He drove away in a white S.U.V. If that helps.
我没能记下车牌号
I didn't get the numbers,
但车挂着北卡罗来纳州的车牌
But they were North Carolina plates.
"人类的第一次起飞"
"First in flight."
到底要带什么样的护具啊
What kind of protection?
莱恩和埃斯波西托正在排查
So Ryan and Esposito are running down everyone
所有拥有紫色通行证的人
That was issued a purple pass
来确认那位克里弗的身份
to see if they can I.D. our Creaver.
明早之前  我们应该会有所收获
We should have something by tomorrow morning.
我想  正如你所说的  卡塞尔
I mean, it's just like you said, Castle.
那套戏服使得凶手的身份难以辨认
That costume allowed our killer to strike unseen.
他当然会装扮成克里弗
And of course he's gonna be a creaver.
它们可是"星云九号"航队
I mean, they're the sworn enemies
不共戴天的仇敌呢
Of the "Nebula-9" Crew.
卡塞尔
Castle?
我看上去有什么变化吗
Do I look different to you?
没有啊  怎么了
No. Why?
我只是觉得有股刺痛
Just, I feel so tingly.
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
我要像绿巨人那样变异了
I'm beginning to mutate like the hulk or the thing
或者更糟糕  我的头发会变成什么样
Or worse, the leader. What would happen to my hair?
变成曼哈顿博士比较好
I prefer Dr. Manhattan.
蓝肤色更能衬出你的蓝眼睛
The blue skin-- brings out your blue eyes.
我不是跟你开玩笑
This isn't funny.
要是那把激光枪影响了我的生育能力怎么办
What if firing that blaster made me infertile?
你还想添孩子吗
You want more kids?
我希望能有选择的余地啊
Well, I'd like the option.
我觉得你会没事的  卡塞尔
Well, I think you're gonna be fine, Castle.
即使如此  我还是得洗个澡
All the same, I should decontaminate.
用滚烫的水洗净身上的激光
Take a silkwood shower.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis.
你在这儿干嘛呢
What are you doing here?
我猜想  在那件事发生后
I thought maybe, after what happened,
你可能想找我谈谈
That you'd want to talk about it.
不  我不想  你呢
No. Me? No. You?
不想
No.
我们已经排查了使用过紫色通行证
Hey, so we found out that valet parking
找人代客泊车的人
comes with those purple passes.
只有一个参加派对的人
And there was only one attendee
有挂着北卡罗来纳州牌照的越野车
that had a white S.U.V. with North Carolina plates.
西蒙·维斯波特
Simon Westport.
他被州骑警拦下时
He was on 295 heading south
正沿着295号洲际公路向北行驶
when state troopers pulled him over.
他的车后备箱里有一套克里弗的戏服
He had a creaver outfit in his trunk.
你认得这个吗  西蒙
Do you recognize this, Simon?
这是一把钍晶喷气枪
It's a thorian blaster.
知道它还是什么吗
You know what else it is?
它是杀死安娜贝尔·柯林斯的凶器
It's the gun that killed Anabelle Collins.
有人装扮成克里弗买了这把枪
Bought by a guy dressed as a creaver
他是最后一个见到死者的人
who was seen with the victim before she died.
事情不是你们想的那样
This is not what it looks like.
这是我买给她的礼物
I bought that for her as a gift.
你给她买了一把收藏型实弹激光枪
You bought her a live-fire collectible laser gun
-作为礼物  -我没有杀她
- as a gift? - I did not kill her.
警察告诉我之前  我都不知道她死了
I didn't even know she was dead till the police told me.
你跟死者有什么关系
What was your relationship to the victim?
我在新星科幻大会上遇到了安娜贝尔  大约五年前
I met Anabelle at supernovacon, like, five years ago,
我们就对上眼了
and we just clicked.
听着
Look,
在科幻大会那几天  你能扮成任何你想成为的人
At the con, you can be anyone you want to be for a few days.
我们就勾搭上了
So we'd hook up.
我跟她只是"明年此时再会"的关系
It was a "Same time next year" Kind of thing.
那你怎么解释
So how does that square
把她留在酒吧里哭
with you leaving her at the bar crying?
好吧  当晚的确发生了些事情
Okay, something did happen at the party that night,
不过跟我无关
But not with me.
我把喷气枪给她  她特别兴奋
I gave her the blaster. She was thrilled.
我出去接了个电话
I left to take a phone call.
回来之后  有个人在烦她
I come back, and there's a guy hassling her.
关于什么的
About what?
我不知道  不过他要强吻她
I don't know, but he tried to kiss her.
她给了他一个耳光
She slapped him in the face.
我走近她的时候  他已经走了
By the time I got to her, he had already taken off.
不过她很伤心  跟我说她需要空间
But she's all upset about it. She tells me she needs space.
所以她拿着激光枪走了
So she takes the blaster and leaves.
后来第二天我去看她怎么样了
So I track her down the next day to see if she's okay,
她无缘无故说再也不办新星科幻大会了
and out of nowhere she says that she's done with supernovacon
我们之间也结束了
And she's done with me.
所以我就退了酒店  走了
So I checked out of my hotel and I left.
你能描述一下那个人吗
Can you describe this guy?
能
Yeah.
他是跟她一起做网络剧的
He's the guy she did those webisodes with--
戴维斯
Davis.
听起来不论戴维斯和安娜贝尔之间有什么
So sounds like whatever happened between Davis and Anabelle
真的伤了她的感情
Really did a number on her.
然后突然  她要甩了西蒙  放弃科幻大会
All of a sudden, she was ready to ditch Simon and the convention.
我们跟戴维斯谈过
We talked to Davis.
他没提到任何小意外
He never mentioned any incident.
说明他有所隐瞒
Which means he's hiding something.
要么就是他杀了她
Either that or he killed her.
你们告诉我  我头发是不是变少了
Hey. Tell me, you guys, do you think my hair is thinning?
你没脱发  卡塞尔
You're not losing your hair, Castle.
那么如果我明天变成秃顶
Okay, so if I wake up bald tomorrow,
你还会被我吸引吗
You'll still be attracted to me?
天呐  你不会了
Oh, my god. You wouldn't.
我可没那么说
I didn't say that.
是没说  可你犹豫了
No, but you were thinking it.
我能从你的
I can see it in your...
就你这南瓜头  老兄
With that pumpkin head? Dude.
戴维斯  你跟安娜贝尔·柯林斯
Davis, what was your relationship
有什么关系
With Anabelle Collins?
告诉过你们  我们是朋友
I told you before. We were friends.
只是朋友吗  还是你想更进一步
Was friendship enough or did you want more?
有目击者在开幕之夜派对上
Witnesses saw you with Anabelle
看到你和安娜贝尔
at the opening night party.
貌似她对你的示爱
It sounds like she didn't respond too well
-反应激烈  -为什么呢
- to your advances. - And why would she?
我是说  你已经跟她的好友
I mean, you were already in a relationship
在交往
With her best friend.
你为什么还要冒险去跟她调情
Why would you risk it all by making a pass at her?
只有一个原因  爱
Only one reason. Love.
但你在跟奥德丽交往
But you were with Audrey.
曾经  是的
I was. I am.
但我爱的一直是安娜贝尔
But it was always Anabelle.
告诉我们发生了什么吧
Why don't you tell us what happened?
那天晚上
That night
我喝了几杯
I'd had a few drinks,
看到她和那个克里弗在派对上
and I saw her with that... Creaver at the party.
他们打得火热
And they were all over each other.
我很难过
And it killed me.
再也忍不下去了
I couldn't take it anymore.
我必须告诉她我的感受
I had to tell her how I really felt,
然后她
And she...
她说了很过分的话
she said terrible things.
她说我毁掉了一切
She said that I had ruined everything,
她必须要去告诉奥德丽
That she was gonna have to tell Audrey.
于是  我不知道该怎么办
And... I didn't know what else to do.
戴维斯  你杀了安娜贝尔吗
Davis, did you kill Anabelle?
没有
No.
不  当时我正穿过大楼
No, I was halfway across the building
去参加化妆舞会
when it happened at the masquerade ball.
你可以去确定
You can check.
听着
Look...
我想挽救跟她的关系
I tried to make things right with her.
我告诉她我醉了  大家都忘掉那件事吧
I told her I was drunk, and we should just forget about it,
但她不听
But she couldn't.
她说活在虚幻中是一回事
She said it was one thing to live a fantasy,
但她不想活在谎言中
but she wasn't gonna live a lie...
这次将是我们最后一次参加科幻大会
And that this was gonna be our last con.
她要终止粉丝体验会吗
She was gonna end the fan experience?
不止是粉丝体验会  是所有一切
Not just the fan experience. Everything.
她说是时候朝前看了
She said it was time to move on.
她已经决定抽出资金
She had decided to cash out
卖掉"星云9号"的版权
and sell the rights to "Nebula-9."
我是说   她接手之前这些一点都不值钱
I mean, they were worthless when she first got 'em,
但是她
but she...
她再次把这部剧炒得这么红火
She made the show popular again.
他们正在洽谈重拍剧集
They were talking about rebooting the series,
甚至可能拍成电影
maybe even doing a movie.
这就意味着有真金白银了
That would mean some real money.
戴维斯  安娜贝尔死后谁能得到版权
Davis, who gets the rights now that Anabelle's dead?
是奥德丽
They go to Audrey.
为什么这么问
Why?
戴维斯的不在场证明成立了
So Davis' alibi checks out.
-算是吧  -算是
- Sort of. - Sort of?
主办方确认他9点半到了派对
Yeah, organizers confirm that he arrived at the party at 9:30,
但是所有人都戴着面具
But everyone was masked.
所以他随时可以溜出去作案
So he could have slipped out at anytime.
安娜贝尔要抽出资金是认真的
Hey. So Anabelle was serious about cashing out.
她桌上有一份来自传奇视野制片厂的邀约
She had an offer on the table from epicscope productions.
几个月来她都拒绝出售
she'd been refusing to sell for months,
但她死亡当天  去了一通电话
But the day she died, she put in a call
说准备答应交易
saying she was ready to make that deal.
多少钱
For how much?
250万美金
$2 and a half million.
这就是杀人动机
That's motive.
太疯狂了
That's madness.
250万买那个破片子
$2.5 mil for that god-awful show?
不过现在她死了  钱都得付给奥德丽
But now that she's dead, they're gonna have to pay Audrey.
尸骨未寒她就等不及了
And she didn't even wait for the body to get cold.
安娜贝尔遇害之后的那个早上
The morning after Anabelle was killed,
奥德丽给传奇视野打了个电话
Audrey put in a call to Epicscope.
他们今天完成了交易
They closed the deal today.
没错  我卖掉了版权  怎么了
Yeah, I sold the rights. I mean, so what?
这一切都是安娜贝尔的
All this... this is all Anabelle.
她不在了继续拍下去还有什么意义
What's the point in doing it without her?
只不过  你本来就不打算
Except you weren't going to be doing it with her
再继续与她共事了  对吧
much longer, were you?
我不明白你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
你跟安娜贝尔合作多年
You worked for years helping Anabelle
帮她提高了"星云9号"的人气
bring "Nebula-9" back to life.
如果她要卖版权  一切都白忙活了
If she sold the rights, all this would go away,
你什么都得不到
leaving you with nothing.
你不能让她这么做  对不对
And you couldn't let her do that, could you?
这说法简直令人作呕
That is a disgusting thing to say.
她是我最要好的朋友
She was my best friend.
她被害那晚你在哪
Where were you the night that she was killed?
我不会再回答任何问题了
I'm not gonna answer any more of your questions.
我们要让
Let's make sure
历史永远记住
that history never forgets
企业号
the name "Enterprise."
嗯  好的  谢了  莱恩
Yeah, okay. Thanks, Ryan.
奥德丽在晚上9:48用过宾馆房卡
So Audrey's hotel key card was used at 9:48 P.M.
之后整晚就没有动静了
and then it wasn't used again the rest of the night.
她也有可能半掩房门
Well, she could've slipped out,
然后溜出去
left her door ajar.
这样能有足够的时间到这里来
That would have given her enough time to get down here.
是没错  可是卡塞尔
Yeah, but, Castle,
我们手上只有间接证据
all we have is circumstantial evidence
以及推测性不在场证明
and soft alibis.
我们得拿到确凿的证据才行
We've gotta get something more concrete.
我都说不清有几次
I can't tell you how many times
我梦到自己身处这艘飞船内了
I have had dreams about being in this very ship.
是春梦吗
Sexy dreams?
要知道实践自己的幻想
You know, it's never too late
永远都不会太晚
to live out your fantasy.
你没忘记这里还是一个犯罪现场吧
You do realize that this is still a crime scene?
对噢  真恶
Oh, right. Ew.
就是
Yeah.
你说的没错
You're right, okay?
这剧确实挺傻的
It was a stupid show.
情节俗套又夸张
It was cheesy and melodramatic.
一群军校学员
I mean, a handful of academy cadets
在进行训练任务
on a training mission,
然后突然地球被毁
and suddenly, the earth is destroyed
他们成了最后的人类
and they're all that's left of humanity?
我完全理解你为什么讨厌这剧
I completely understand why you hated it.
可是卡塞尔  我也理解为什么人们会喜欢它
But, Castle, I also understand why people loved it,
为什么安娜贝尔喜欢它
why Anabelle loved it.
它述说的是第一次离家
It was about leaving home for the first time,
寻找真实的自我
about searching for your identity
并进行改变的故事
and making a difference.
我喜欢扮成克洛伊上尉
I loved dressing up like Lieutenant Chloe.
她不在乎周围人对她的看法
She didn't care what anybody thought about her,
我曾经也是这样
and I kinda did at that time.
她是一个科学家  也是一个勇士
I mean, she was a scientist and a warrior,
不管外表上看是什么样  这是她的本质
And that was all in spite of the way that she looked.
我觉得自己可以成为任何人
It was like I could be anything,
并且不用做取舍
and I didn't have to choose.
所以别再嘲笑这剧了  行吗
So don't make fun, okay?
行
Okay.
再说了  情节俗套也不影响
Besides, it didn't hurt
那套制服把我的腿衬得很好看
that my legs looked great in her outfit.
这点我毫无异议...
Oh, of that I have no dou...
怎么了
What's wrong?
我的手
My hand.
这是怎么回事
I mean, what does that mean?
你刚刚破解了我们的案子
That means you just solved our case.
谢谢大家今天抽空前来
Thank you, everyone, for coming in today.
我怎么记得好像这是强制性的
I was under the impression I didn't have a choice.
没错
You didn't.
我不明白  我们到底来干嘛的
I don't understand. What are we doing here?
现在屋里的每一个人都跟死者有关系
Everyone in this room had a relationship with the victim.
你们每一个人不是有动机就是有机会下手
Each of you had either motive or opportunity to kill her.
弗赖伊女士  请问能否帮忙
Uh, Ms. Frye, would you do me the honor
即兴出演一小段
of a little improvisation?
得了吧  她需要剧本才行
Trust me, that woman needs a script.
我很乐意帮忙
I'm happy to help.
弗赖伊女士就是安娜贝尔·柯林斯
Ms. Frye will be playing Anabelle Collins.
我是凶手
I will be the killer.
安娜贝尔遇害当晚
Anabelle had the murder weapon on her
手中拿着凶器
The night she died.
别担心  这只是个玩具
Don't worry. This one's just a toy.
现在凶手在跟安娜贝尔当面对质
Now the killer confronts Anabelle.
安娜贝尔  很有可能为了保护自己
Anabelle, presumably to protect herself,
掏出了喷气枪
drew her blaster.
他们便开始了争斗
They struggled for the gun.
凶手用力
The killer overpow--
别用太大劲
I-I need you to resist just a little less.
我说什么来着
Told ya.
然后
And...
抢下了枪
wrenched free the weapon.
安娜贝尔便被自己的钍晶喷气枪杀害了
Anabelle was slain by her own thorian blaster.
咝
Zap.
演过头了吧
Overacting much?
闭嘴吧你  加布里埃尔
Shut up, Gabriel.
然后
At that point,
凶手把安娜贝尔的尸体
the killer stashed Anabelle's body
藏进了先知舱
in the oracle pod,
而且对于使用钍晶喷气枪会留下
not knowing that by firing the thorian blaster,
关键性证据以这点毫不知情
they were leaving behind crucial evidence.
枪内喷射出的能量
The energy emission from the gun
会在开枪者的手部皮肤上留下痕迹
left a superficial burn on the killer's skin...
该痕迹在紫外线灯下才会显现
which is visible under U.V. light.
凶手身上就有这样的痕迹
Branding our murderer with the mark of cain.
或者对"星云9号"的粉丝们来说
Or for you "Nebula-9" fans,
这叫进化疹
the mark of claderesh.
西蒙  能到前面来吗
Simon, could you step forward, please?
请伸出双手
Could you hold out your hands?
谢谢
Thank you.
戴维斯
Davis.
左手也要检查
Your left hand as well.
谢谢
Thank you.
奥德丽
Audrey.
沃特斯先生
Mr. Winters?
听着  我...
Look, I, um...
我能解释
I can explain.
是你干的
It was you?
不  我有不在场证明
No. I have an alibi.
不在场证明可以伪造
Alibis can be bought.
我没有杀安娜贝尔
I didn't kill Anabelle.
那为什么你的手会发光
Then why is your hand glowing?
因为
Because...
当我知道有个书呆子能造出真的钍晶喷气枪时
when I found out some nerd was making real thorian blasters,
我觉得应该由我来拥有它
I figured if anybody should have one, it should be me.
我可是麦克斯舰长
I'm Captain Max.
所以我跟着他  买下了最后一把枪
So I tracked him down and I bought the last one.
这是今早弄上的
This is from this morning.
我在宾馆的房间里开了一枪
I shot it in my hotel room.
墙上还留着洞
There's a hole in the wall.
你们可以去查
You can check.
史黛芬妮  你要去哪里
Stephanie, where are you going?
我只是想...
I was just gonna--
呆在那里别动
Hold it right there!
你也听他说了
You heard the man.
这把枪能置人死地
This one's deadly.
谁都别动  否则我一枪毙了他
Nobody moves or I put a hole in his head.
只有我一个人觉得此情此景异常熟悉吗
Am I the only one that finds this situation eerily familiar?
史黛芬妮  为什么
Stephanie, why?
你知道我花了多长时间
Do you know how long I have worked
才摆脱了克洛伊上尉这个形象
to get away from Lieutenant Chloe,
才真正脱离了这部烂剧吗
to get away from the stench of this show?
这个粉丝体验会就够糟了
The fan experience was bad enough,
而她居然还要卖掉版权
but she was gonna sell the rights,
这一切又会重头开始
and it was gonna start all over again--
电影系列  周边产品
the movies, the product lines,
克洛伊上尉摇头娃娃
Lieutenant Chloe bobbleheads!
你知道为了取得成功  做真正的女演员
Do you know how hard I worked to make something of myself,
我有多努力吗
to become a real actress?
算了吧  史黛芬
Oh, come on, Steph.
你的演技刻板生硬
You can't act your way out of paper bag.
我唯一的慰藉是  这次杀了你以后
The only solace I have is, this time when I kill you,
可没有什么安多利神使能让你复活了
there is not an Andorian Empath to bring you back from the dead.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
为了用这招  我都等十年了  泼妇
I've been waiting ten years to do that, bitch.
没人能接管我的飞船
Nobody takes over my ship.
如果让特技演员做  肯定容易得多
It's a lot easier when the stunt guys do it.
你知道自己有多幸运吗
Do you realize how lucky you are?
你很可能会被杀的
You could've gotten yourself killed.
不可能
Not even.
我换成了道具枪
I had it on stun.
史黛芬妮·弗赖伊
Stephanie Frye,
你因涉嫌谋杀安娜贝尔·柯林斯而被捕了
you're under arrest for the murder of Anabelle Collins.
能让我说吗
May I?
愿幸运  指引你的航程
And may fortune guide your journey.
医生说  我的手几天后就不会发光了
The doctor says my hand's gonna stop glowing in a few days.
所以不会突变了
So no mutant powers?
是的  这次不会了
No, not this time,
至少我的头发不会掉光了
but at least my hair's not falling out.
那你呢  你  你怎么样
What about you? How are-- how are you doing?
我很好  怎么了
I'm fine. Why?
看着自己的偶像堕落一定不好受
Well, it's hard to see your idols fall.
卡塞尔  史黛芬妮·弗赖伊不是我的偶像
Oh, Castle. Stephanie Frye was never my idol.
克洛伊上尉才是
Lieutenant Chloe was.
在我看来  她仍然在那里
And as far as I'm concerned, she's still out there
惩恶除奸  拯救人类
fighting evil and saving humanity.
任何只顾自己的演员都无法将她从我心中抹去
And no self-centered actor is ever gonna take that from me.
你知道吗
And you know what?
如果真拍了电影
If they do make a movie,
我会排队第一个去看
I'm gonna be first in line to see it.
这就是想象的力量
Ah, such is the power of fantasy.
说到想象
And... speaking of fantasies,
我们来真实体验一把怎么样
how about we live out one of yours?
来一场小型"星云9号"真人秀吧
What do you say to a little "Nebula-9" cosplay?
来吧  会很有趣的
Come on. It'll be fun.
我为你做一周的床上早餐
I'll serve you breakfast in bed for a week.
还帮你洗衣服
And I'll do your laundry.
好吧
Okay, fine.
你真想看我穿以前的戏服吗
Do you really want to see me in one of my old costumes?
是的  求你了
Yes, please.
那你得保证
Then you have to promise
你要陪我看"星云9号"系列
that you're gonna watch a "Nebula-9" marathon with me.
我
I...
还有
And...
不准取笑它
no making fun.
你还真会讨价还价
You drive a hard bargain,
不过  好吧
but okay.
我待会去你家
I'll see you at your place.
你保证不许笑
Okay, promise not to laugh.
我保证  快点  别磨蹭了
I promise. Come on. Quit stalling.
快点出来吧
Come out already.
准备好了吗
Ready?
好了
Ready.
你喜欢吗
Do you like it? Huh?
这不是你...  不是...
That's not what you-- that's not...
你想继续吗  卡塞尔
You want to make out, Castle?
不  我...
No. I--
来吧  点到即止  吻我  吻这儿
Come on. Just quick snot. Over here, on the lips.
这不是你梦寐以求的吗
Isn't this what your dreams are made of?
卡塞尔
Castle.
我们要滚床单吗
Are we gonna make out?
也许我们该开始看"星云9号"了
Maybe we should start with the "Nebula-9" marathon.